한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
재배포 허용. 수정은 제작자와 협의 하에
- 잘들 들어가게
- 안녕히 계세요.
- Good night, ladies.
- Good night.
- 들어가는 길 조심들 하고.
- 네 고마워요
- Get home safe.
- Thanks.
그래요, 내일 뵈어요
Okay. We'll see
you tomorrow.
안녕 아들!
Hey, kid.
15분만 기다려
금방 갈게
I'll be there in 15.
아니지 아니지
한 턱 내는건 내가 아니라 너지.
No, no, you're buying.
이제 합격해서 봉급도
나보다 많이 받게 될 사람이 한 턱 내야지
You got a big boy job now
and a big boy paycheck.
그래?
Uh-huh.
알았어, 잠깐 끊자 아들
문 좀 잠그게
Hey, let me go, son.
I'm locking up.
아니야, 나머지는
만나서 얘기하자
No, we'll talk
when I get there.
나도 사랑한단다,
그리고 네가 정말 자랑스럽단다
I love you, too.
And, hey, I'm proud of you.
빨리 해 얼른!
Come on,
hurry up, come on!
빨리 챙기라고!
Hurry up! Get it!
그렇게 된 거예요
That's it.
총소리가 들려서 돌아보니
그 형씨가 총에 맞아 있었고,
저는 그냥 도망갔죠
Shots went off, I saw the dude
get hit, and I ran.
한 블럭을 내려가서 확인해보니
Got around the block
이렇게 어깨가
타들어가는 듯한 통증을 느꼈죠
and I felt this...
burning feeling in my shoulder.
제가 아는 건 여기까지예요
That's all I saw.
That "dude" was an
off-duty police officer,
그 '형씨'는 수표현금교환소에서
투잡을 뛰던 비번 경찰관이라네
moonlighting at the
check cashing store.
자네는 정말 단 1초라도 돌아서서
Did it occur to you,
did it cross your mind
총상을 입은 사람을 도와야겠다는
생각이 들지 않았던 건가?
for one second to
go back and help him?!
저도 총상을 입었다구요
저도 피해자예요
I mean, I was shot, too.
핑계 대지 말게
자네는 마약 사건에 대해
법정수배가 걸려 있어서
And you knew you had an active
bench warrant on a drug case,
일이 귀찮게 되고 싶지
않았던 것 뿐이었겠지
so you didn't
want to stick around.
자네는 괜히 걸려서 법정에 서고 싶지 않아서
죽어가는 사람을 길바닥에 버려둔 것이야
You'd rather leave a man die
in the street than go to court.
형사님 제발요, 저는 그런 걸로
감옥에 다시 들어갈 수 없어요
Hey, please, I can't
go back inside on that warrant.
전 애도 딸려 있는걸요
I got a kid.
저도 정말 119에 신고를 하고 싶었어요
정말이예요
I wanted to call, okay?
I really did.
그런데 무서웠어요
I was scared.
단순히 제가 경찰에 체포될걸
걱정해서 그런건 아니였어요
Maybe I wasn't thinking
about the cop, all right?
안녕히 계세요.
Good night.
그거 알아요?
You know what?
제가 법적으로 경찰을
도와야만 할 의무는 없잖아요
There's no law that says
I have to help you guys.
그러니까 저에게 조금이라도
감사의 표시를 해줘야 아닌가요?
So, you know what'd be nice?
Just a little, maybe,
"협조에 감사합니다 롬바르도 씨" 정도?
"Hey, thank you for
cooperating, Mr. Lombardo."
네놈이 총상으로 병원에 왔으니
You wouldn't even be
talking to us if the hospital
병원에서 절차대로 신고를 해서 출동을 한거야
당연한 일을 가지고 네놈한테 고마워해야 하나?
hadn't called to report you
coming in with a gunshot wound.
그 경찰 아저씨는 어떻대요?
Hey, how's that
cop doing, anyway?
저 아래 수술실에서
필사적으로 고군분투하고 있지
He's down the hall,
fighting for his life.
일어나
Get up.
- 왜요?
- 돌아서라고
- What?
- Turn around. Turn around.
아야 아야!
Ow. Ow!
알았어요 알았어요
진정해 봐요!
Hey, okay. Relax, relax!
이게 무슨 짓이예요?
What the hell's going on?!
자네는 길건너편에서 뛰어가다가
총상을 입은게 아니었어
You weren't across the street
running when you got shot.
총알이 자네 어깨를 관통할 때
You were standing
right over the officer
자네는 그 경찰관 바로 근처에 서 있었지
when the bullet went
through your shoulder.
자네는 무고한 목격자가 아니야
거짓말쟁이일 뿐이지
You're no innocent
bystander, you're a liar.
한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
CSI:NY S09E12
Civilized Lies
재배포 허용, 무단수정 금지
♪ Out here in the fields
♪ I fight for my meals
♪ I get my back into my living
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
오 이런!
Oh, snap!
딱걸렸어 이자식들 그렇지?
I got all y'all! What?
머리스타일들이 하나같이 똑같군
Looks like they all
go to the same barber.
그러게요, 농담 않고
친형제들일지도 몰라요
Uh-huh, no kidding.
They could be brothers.
- 나머지 비디오는 어때?
- 그게..
What about the rest of the video?
차는 보이는데
뚜렷하게 보이질 않아요
I see the car,
just not really clear.
증인이 번호판 넘버를 알려줬는데
Witness took
down the plate.
어제 도난 신고된 차더군
Car was reported
stolen yesterday.
제가 이 녹화영상을
처음부터 끝까지 샅샅이 봤는데요
Okay, I went through the
entire video, open to closing,
롬바르도는 커녕 비슷한 사람도
전혀 화면에 잡히지 않았어요
and no one resembling
Lombardo came in and out.
사건에 연관되었다고 보기에는
영상에 찍히지 않았다는게 이상해요
If he's involved,
he's not in this video.
증인들이 하는 소리는
하나같이 다 똑같아요
All the witnesses
have the same story:
'대머리의 흑인 남성 3명'이요
all right, three bald,
African-American males.
롬바르도를 언급한 사람은
아무도 없어요
No one puts Lombardo
at the scene.
그런데 과학수사에서는
롬바르도에 연관성이 있다고 나왔어
But the science does.
I examined
those gunshot wounds.
총상들을 전부 분석해봤는데
롬바르도가 총에 맞을 때,
Lombardo was standing
directly over Riley,
롬바르도는 라일리 경관의
바로 앞에 마주보면서 서 있었어
facing him,
when Riley shot him.
총알은 롬바르도의 어깨를 관통해
Bullet traveled
through his shoulder,
맞은편 거리에까지 뚫고 나갔지
ended up on
the other side of the street.
라일리 경관의 38구경 권총은
몸 바로 근처에서 발견되었어
Riley's .38 was recovered
right near his body.
롬바르도는 라일리 경관의
총에 맞은게 아니야
Lombardo was not
shot with that gun
다른 총으로 맞은 것이지
somewhere else later on.
롬바르도가 무슨 투명인간이라도
Unless Lombardo
had some sort of
되지 않고서야 불가능한 일이예요
magical cloaking device,
how did he end up
어떻게 롬바르도는 목격자 하나 없이
범죄 현장에서 총을 맞은걸까요?
in the crime scene, get shot,
without anybody seeing him?
마크 라일리 경관님은
제가 뉴욕에서
Mark Riley was the first officer
맡았던 첫 범죄 사건 현장에서
처음으로 만났던 경관이었어요
at one of the first crime
scenes I worked in the city.
정말 인상깊은 분이었어요
He really made
an impression on me.
친절하면서도
맡은 일에 매우 전문적이셨고,
He was so nice,
very professional...
자기 임무에 대해 박식하셨죠
really knew his stuff.
그 이후 종종 법정에서도
마주치고는 했죠
I bumped into him
at the courthouse a few times.
그럴때마다 자기 가족 이야기르
하시곤 했는데..
Always talking
about his family.
그랬구나
Mm.
아버지의 직업을 따라
미래를 결정한 아들이 있었나보군
Looks like he's got someone
following in his footsteps.
안녕하세요, 제이슨 라일리라고 합니다
Hi, I'm Jason Riley.
안녕하세요, 저는 조 댄빌 형사예요
Hi.
Jo Danville, detective.
저희는 과학수사연구소에서 왔어요
We're from the crime lab.
저는 린지 메서 형사입니다
Hi, I'm Detective
Lindsay Messer.
-제 아버지가..
-저희도 알아요
- Uh, my dad's...
- We know.
아버님의 쾌유를
전적으로 기원합니다
We're pulling for him.
누가 이런짓을 했는지
혹시 파악이 되시나요?
Do you have any idea
who did this?
아직요,
하지만 저희 모든 인력을 동원해
Not yet, but we
have a whole team
of detectives working on it.
범인을 추적하고 있어요.
범인을 잡을 때까지
밤새 일할 각오가 되어있어요
No one's going
home till we do.
그러면 형사님 팀은..
So, what?
You're, um...
저희 아버지가 돌아가시면
시신을 부검하기 위해 오신 건가요?
here to process his body if...
아녜요, 저희는 아버님 수술이 끝나면
No. No, we're here
to collect evidence
피해 당시 입고 있던 옷에서
증거물을 채집해 조사할 계획이예요
in his clothing once he
pulls through surgery.
아버지는 사고를 당하시기 직전에
I was, I was talking to him
저와 통화를 하고 계셨었죠
on the phone
just before he got shot.
같이 야간근무를 빼서
We both got off at midnight,
근사한 곳에서 저녁을 먹으면서
and we were gonna
go to the diner,
커피도 한잔 하고
밤참을 즐길 생각이었죠
have coffee and a midnight snack.
통화 당시에 혹시 무언가
걱정하는듯한 말씀을 하신 적이 있었나요?
Did he sound worried or
concerned about anything?
아뇨, 조금 급하게
전화를 끊으시긴 했는데
No. I mean, he kind of
hurried off the phone
like he was distracted,
but he-he gets that way
늘상 그렇게 전화를 끊으셨거든요
뭔가 일이 바쁘면 항상 그러셨어요
when he's trying to do
three things at one time.
전화를 끊으면서
'나도 널 사랑한단다, 네가 정말 자랑스럽단다'
라고 말씀하시긴 했죠
He said, um, "I love you
and I'm proud of you," though.
좋은 거죠, 그렇겠죠?
That's pretty good,
right?
아버지에게서 마지막으로 듣게 될
말로는 정말 좋은 말이 되겠죠?
If it's the last thing
your father ever says to you?
그렇게 생각하지 말아요
Don't think like that.
아버님을 그 동안 지켜봤지만
아버님은 정말 강인하신 분이예요
From what I know about
your dad, he's a fighter.
물론이고 말고요
Yeah, he is.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
신사 숙녀 여러분,
Ladies and gentlemen,
지난 밤, 비번의 NYPD 경관이
last night,
an off-duty NYPD officer
퀸즈에서 강도 사고로
총을 맞는 사고가 발생했습니다
was shot during
a burglary in Queens.
기쁘게도 피해를 입은 경관은
무사히 수술을 끝마쳤고,
But I'm happy to say that
the officer is out of surgery
가족들이 옆에서 열심히
간호해주고 있습니다.
and his family is by his side.
좋아!
Yes!
그러나 한가지 주의드릴 점은
아직 중대한 위기를 넘긴 것은 아니며,
But I will caution you,
we are not out of the woods yet.
향후 24~48시간이 생사를 결정지을
The next 24 to 48 hours
will be crucial in determining
큰 고비가 될 것이라는 점입니다.
his condition going forward.
수고한 저희 외상 담당 팀에게
감사를 전하고 싶고..
I want to thank
my trauma team...
네놈한테 좋은 소식이구만
That's good news for you.
다행히 살아나실 것 같아
Looks like he's going to make it.
잘 했어!
Well played.
뭐하는거야?
What are you doing?
그 뉴스 영상 자료를
얼마나 공들여서 만들었는데?
That press conference is golden.
2년이나 지났잖아요
It's two years old.
이제 새로 찍어야죠
We need an upgrade.
맞는 말이군
You have a point.
반장님은 저 자가
입을 열 때까지 기다리라고 하셔요
Mac wants us to wait for him.
그래서 어떻게 생각해요?
So, what do you think?
아직도 알아내기가 어려워요?
Tough nut to crack?
저 자는 겁먹었어
He's scared.
하지만 내 직감 상
저 자가 라일리 경관이
살아있다고 생각한다면
But my gut tells me,
as long as he thinks
곧 입을 열게 될거야
Officer Riley is still alive,
he'll keep talking.
♪
이해하기 쉽게 얘기해주지
I'm gonna make it
real simple for you.
네 어깨 앞에 난 구멍은
총탄이 처음 뚫고 들어간 흔적이야
(enterance wound : 사입부(射入部))
The hole in the front of your
shoulder is an entrance wound.
네 등 쪽에 난 구멍은
총탄이 뚫고 나간 흔적이고
(exit wound : 자출구(刺出口))
The hole in the back
is an exit wound.
발포자는
1.8m 정도 거리에서
The bullet entered
at an upward angle
윗방향으로 총을 발사했고
총탄은 네 몸을 통과했지
within six feet of the shooter.
그 말인 즉슨
용의자가 자네에게 총을 쐈을때
That means you had to
be standing directly
over and facing Officer Riley
when he shot you.
자네는 라일리 경관을 가까이에서
마주보고 있었다는 것이지
저는 반대편에서
뛰어가고 있었다고요
I was across the street,
running away.
몇 번을 얘기해요?
Like I told you.
사실을 얘기하고 있잖아요
What? That's the truth.
형사님이 원하시면
거짓말이라도 할 수 있어요
I mean, I could lie
if you want me to.
그게 소원이시면 제가 어떻게
말해야할지 대사라도 알려주세요
You know, just tell me
what you want me to say.
자네와 같은 패였던
세 남자의 이름을 대게
I want you to say the names
of the three men you were with.
_
내 눈 똑바로 봐!
Look at me.
이름을 대! 당장!
The names! Now!
얼른!
Come on, get up.
변명이라도 대보시지
Give me an excuse.
기대도 안했다
I didn't think so.
이 쓰레기 자식하고는
더 이상 상대하지 않겠네
I'm done with this
piece of garbage.
자네 하고 싶은대로
마음껏 해도 좋네
Do whatever you
want with him.
이런, 반장님의 나쁜 경찰 모드를
보고싶지는 않았는데요
Damn. I would not want
to get on your bad side.
그래서 형사님은 이제
좋은 경찰 역할이라도 하시게요?
What, now you gonna
play good cop?
솔직히 말해서
나도 널 어찌해야 할 지 모르겠다
Be honest with you,
I don't know what to do.
반장님이 보통
좋은 경찰 역할이었는데
He's usually the good cop.
반장님은 내 상관이기도 하지
He's also the boss.
다른 사람은 몰라도
반장님 성질은 건드리지 않는게
And the last guy
너한테 있어서도 좋을거야
in this building you
want to piss off.
이봐요 형씨,
증인이 있다면서요
Look, man,
you got a witness
데려와봐요, 그 증인이
절 알아보나 확인해보면 되잖아요
who can I.D. me,
bring him in.
또, DNA 뭐시기라도
검출되면 그걸로 제 거랑 대조해봐요
You got any of that DNA crap,
bring it on.
그렇게 못할거면
증거를 가져다 영장을 받아오세요
Otherwise, take me to court
on that warrant,
제 증언은 거짓이 아니니까요
because I told you what I saw.
봐봐
Look...
너 말이야
꽤 똘똘한 놈 같아보이는데
you seem like a smart guy.
우리가 증인이 있다면
널 진작에 세워서 인상 대조를
해봤을거라는걸 잘 알겠네
So you know if we had a witness,
you'd be standing in a lineup.
나는 거짓말같은건 하지 않아
I'm not gonna lie.
다 영장을 받아다 이러고 있는거라고
All I got you on is
that warrant right now.
그럼 무슨 근거로 제가
거짓말을 한다고 확신하는거예요?
So what makes you so sure
that I'm lying?
네 증언은 말이 안되거든
Because your story
makes no sense.
네 증언대로라면
사건이 그렇게 날 수가 없어
It couldn't have happened
the way you said.
너무 무른데요?
He's being too soft.
으음
Mm.
침착하게 하는 것이라네
He's being patient.
저 자의 취조를 맡기에는
플랙이 누구보다도 뛰어나다네
I can't think of anybody
I'd rather have in that room.
너는 라일리 경관의 38구경 권총에
총상을 입었다고 증언했지
You got hit with a bullet from
Officer Riley's five-shot .38.
38구경은 그리 세지 않은 총이야
That thing's a pea-shooter.
약하기 때문에 건너편의 사람을
간신히 스치거나 할 수나 있지
It wouldn't barely break the
skin from across the street.
그런 걸로 건너편의 사람에게
It definitely would not go
clean through you shoulder
관통상을 입힐 정도의 치명상을 낼 수 없어
from that distance.
안 된다고
Impossible.
나도 이 짓거리
하루이틀 한거 아니거든?
I've been doing this
for a long time.
나도 많은 진술을 들어왔지
I've heard a lot of stories.
니 진술은 좋다고 볼 수 없어
This one's bad.
앤써니, 내 말 들어
Anthony, listen to me.
네가 강도를 당하던 경관과
1.8m 정도 거리에 있었다는 것만으로
Being six feet away
from a cop getting robbed
유죄가 된다거나 하지 않아
does not make you
guilty of anything.
그냥 좋지 않은 사건 현장에서
It just means that maybe
you got a little too close
우연히도 너무 가까이에
있었다는것뿐이지
to a bad situation.
모든 증인들이 사건 용의자를
대머리 흑인 3명이라고 밝히고 있어
All of our witnesses say that
three bald black guys did this.
반면 너는 머리도 길고 백인이잖아
You got a full head of hair,
and you look pretty white to me.
뭘 숨기고 있는거야?
What are you hiding?
네 전과 때문에 네 증언을 아무도
Maybe you think no
one will believe you
믿어주지 않을꺼라 생각하는거야?
because of your record?
그런 이유때문이라면
빨리 나한테 말해
If that's it,
you got to tell me,
바깥에 있는 사람들은 지금
이 사건에 책임을 묻고 싶어하고 있고
because the people out there are
looking to put this on someone,
지금으로서 그걸 뒤집어쓸 사람은
너밖에 없거든
and right now, that
someone is you.
아, 이런
Oh, man.
알았어요
All right.
알았어요, 저는 길 건너편에
있던게 아니었어요
I wasn't across the street, okay?
그 자들이 그 경관을 쏜 현장과
I was passing by
on the same side
같은 거리를 지나치고 있었죠
that they shot that cop on.
총소리가 들리기 전까지는
무슨 일인지 알지도 못했어요
I didn't know what was up
till the shots went off.
그러다 저도 총을 맞았고,
I got hit.
그대로 무작정 도망갔죠
I just ran.
정말 이게 사실이예요
I mean, that's it.
저는 그 경관의 총상에
어떠한 책임도 없어요.
I had nothing to do
with that cop getting shot.
넌 대체 왜 이러는거야?
What the hell is wrong with you?
뭐가요?
What?
우리가 진실을 알아내기 위해
Why did we have to
waste all of that time
얼마나 시간을 쏟아부은지 알아?
to get to the truth?
몰라요
I don't know.
펜이랑 종이 가져올테니
I'm coming back with
a pen and a pad.
방금 네 진술을 적도록 해
I want you to write
down your statement.
그래요, 그런데
제가 글을 좀 못 쓰는데요
Yeah, hey,
but I'm no good with spelling.
나도다
Neither am I.
드디어 떡밥을 물었군요
Fish on, the hook is in,
사건 현장과 저 자를
연결시킬 수 있게 되었어요
and we reeled him
into the crime scene.
저 자가 단순히 영장 떄문에
겁먹은건 아니라고 봐
I'm not buying he was scared
because of the warrant.
저 자도 분명 연관되어 있어
He's involved.
잘 했지?
Nice work.
반장님이 저 자 의자를 돌렸을때
정말 통제력을 잃을 뻔했어요
I nearly messed myself when
you spun his chair around.
반장님 표정 봤어요
무슨 생각이세요?
I know that look.
What are you thinking?
저 자가 제 입으로 범죄 현장에
자기가 있었다는 것을 말하긴 했지만
He puts himself at
the crime scene,
우리는 여전히 저 자가 강도 행위에
연관되어있었다는 것을 밝힐
증거가 없는 상태지
but we don't evidence
that proves he was involved
in the robbery.
저 자는 감시카메라
영상에도 찍히지 않았고
He's not on the surveillance tape,
우리는 저 자를 나머지 세 용의자와
연결시킬 증인조차 확보하지 못했지
and we don't have a
witness who can place him
with other three perps.
뭔가 미심쩍어
Something's not right.
♪
제 결과가 더 빨리 나온다에
런치 온 로슨을 걸죠
(Lunch at Lawsons : 미국의 식당 체인)
Lunch at Lawson's says
my results come up first.
그럼 내가 더 빨리나오면
네가 그리말디에서 저녁 쏘는거다?
Dinner, Grimaldi's.
- 콜?
- 그래요 콜!
- You're on.
- Yeah, all right.
라일리 경관의 옷에서 체취한
혈액 샘플은 모두 본인 것으로 밝혀졌어요
All the blood samples I got
from Officer Riley's clothing
타자의 DNA도 없었고요
came back to him;
no foreign DNA.
그리고 옷에서
털 두 조각이 발견되었는데
And I did find two hairs
on his shirt.
모두 인조 성분이었어요.
They were both synthetic.
폴리에스터 아크릴 혼합 소재였죠
Some kind
of polyester-acrylic blend.
끝부분에서는 에폭시 성분이
검출되었고요
They also had epoxy
on the ends.
그 두 놈들은 인조 모발을 사용했군
Two guys did have facial hair.
가짜 수염에서
떨어져나온 것일 수 있어
Could be from a fake beard
or mustache.
"검출 성분 : 실리콘, 라텍스"
그리말디에서 저녁 쏘는거다?
We're going to Grimaldi's.
잠깐만요, 라일리 경관의
손톱 밑에서도
Wait, hold up,
latex and silicone
라텍스랑 실리콘이
나온 것뿐만 아니라
under Riley's fingernails
롬바르도의 어깨를 관통한 총알에서도
and also on
the bullet
라텍스랑 실리콘이 검출되었어요
that went through
Lombardo's shoulder.
인조 모발이 말이지?
And synthetic hairs.
우리가 찾고자 한 것을
찾은것 같아
Think I know
what we're looking for.
제가 글을 꽤 못 쓰죠?
Spelling's pretty bad, right?
끔찍하구만
It's terrible.
"run"의 과거형은 "ran"이지
"runned."라는 단어가 어디 있냐
There no such word as "runned."
It's "ran."
중요한 건 네 진술이
일단 타당하다는 것이고
But the important thing is
that the story makes sense
나도 믿어줄 수 있을 것 같아
and I believe it.
얼른 반장님께 확인을 받으러
갖다드려야겠어
I just got to run it up the
flagpole, check with the bosses.
네 아파트에 수색 영장을
발부해 조사해봤는데
We executed a search
warrant at your apartment,
재미있는 게 몇가지 나오더군
found some
interesting stuff.
많이 보던 것 아닌가?
Look familiar?
이건 어때?
How about this?
이게 너였어
가면을 쓰고 있었던 거야
That's you, wearing this mask.
너는 강도짓을 하던 남자들이
You didn't witness
세 명이 아니라고 증언했었지?
three guys committing a robbery.
너도 한 패였던 거야
You were one of them.
네 살
Four.
네 살 때는 아이들이
똘똘하다고도 하지
They say it's a great age.
그런데 솔직히 말해서
Gonna be honest with you.
난 네 살때 기억같은건 잘 안나
I don't remember it.
네 딸은 내년에 유치원에 들어가겠지
안 그래?
She'll be going to kindergarten
next year, won't she?
학교에 처음 들어간다는 것은
큰 일이지
That first day of school
is always a big one.
어떻게 될지 계산 좀 해보자
Let's figure this out.
경찰관에 대한 살인미수로
Attempted murder
of a police officer,
최하 10년형을 받을 것이고
that's, like,
ten years minimum.
1급 강도,
Robbery one,
실탄이 장전된 화기류의 소지죄,
possession of a loaded firearm,
장물 소지죄,
criminal possession
of stolen property,
이런저런 자잘한 것까지 치면
7~8개 정도 더 붙을 수 있고,
all the other little charges,
add another seven or eight.
내 생각에 넌
최하 15년은 넘게 썩을거야
My guess,
you're looking at 15 minimum.
네 딸의 첫 무도회는
당연히 놓치겠고
Damn, you'll probably
just miss the prom
고등학교 졸업식도
함께할 수 없겠구만
and high school graduation.
별로 신경 안써도 되겠다
그때쯤 되면 네 딸은 아버지인 너도 못 알아볼걸
But no big deal she probably
won't even know you by then.
네 딸은 지금이야
아빠를 보러 갈거라고 약속하겠다만
And your girl will promise,
and she might even mean it,
내가 장담컨대
but I'm telling you this
right now,
네 딸이 미국-캐나다의 국경선에 있는
there is no way
she's gonna schlep up
최고 1급 감옥까지
to some maxi max prison
그 먼 길을 달려서
면회를 올 일은 없을거라는 거야
on the US-Canadian border
to come and see you.
그럴 일은
있을 수가 없어
Not gonna happen.
지금 날 놀려먹는 거예요?
You getting your rocks off?
내 마음에 상처를 주고,
Messing with my heart.
내 가족들을 폄하하면서?
Disrespecting my family.
지금까지 그 의자에
한가하게 쳐앉아서
No more than you've been
getting your rocks off
내 얼굴에다 대고
2시간 내내 거짓말이나 하고 있는
disrespecting me,
sitting in that chair,
네놈이야말로 날 놀려먹는거지!
lying to my face
for the last couple hours!
넌 내 상관 앞에서 날
병신으로 만들어놨어
You made me look like a jackass
in front of my bosses,
내가 널 도와주려
했는데도 불구하고 말이야
and I was trying to help you out!
널 믿었어
I believed you, man.
진짜로 말이야
I really did!
죄송해요
I'm sorry about that.
저희를 지켜보는 사람이 있나요?
Is there people watching us?
지금은 없어
Well, there was.
모두가 와서 지켜보고 있었는데
There was a whole crowd of people.
이제 너랑 나밖에 안남았어
It was standing room only.
이제 볼 것도 없잖아
But there's nothing
to watch anymore.
저편엔 아무도 없어
It's a ghost town
in there now.
모든 관할 경찰이 나가서
Everyone's out in front
of the precinct right now
네놈이 체포되었다는 걸
언론에 밝히고 있어
at a press conference
announcing your arrest.
사건 종결이야
The case is cleared.
경찰에서는 이제
범인을 잡았다고 생각하고 있어
They got their man.
경찰에서는 다른 두 놈을 어떻게
Yeah, they'll say
something brave
쫓아서 찾았는지에 대한 얘기들을 할거고
about going after
the other two guys,
다행히 총상을 입은
경관이 목숨을 건졌다고 말하게 될거야
but at the end of he day,
the cop didn't die.
모두들 범인을 너로
지목할 수 있어서 기뻐하고 있어
They are happy putting
all of this on you.
너는 그래도 상관없겠지만
나는 아니야
And you might be good
with that, but I'm not.
난 진실을 원해
I want the truth.
앤써니!
Anthony,
나는 믿어
네가 그 경관을
I'm pretty sure
you didn't pull the trigger
쏘지 않았는 걸
and shoot that cop.
이 사진은 너한테 돌려줄게
I got to give it to you.
넌 믿을 수 있는 놈이야
You're a stand-up guy.
난 네가 범인이 아니라고 확신해
I don't think
I could do it.
네 공범들은 총 맞은 너를
길가에 버려두고
Those guys drove off
and left you in the street,
차를 타고 도망가버렸어
knowing you were shot.
너만 신세 망친 것 뿐이야
That's messed up.
공범이 누구야?
Who are they?
이름을 대 봐
What are their names?
알았어.
All right.
혹시나 마음이 바뀌면
소리쳐
You think of those names,
you give me a shout.
잠깐 바람 좀 쐬고 올란다
I'll be around for a bit.
끝내 생각이 안 바뀌면
법정에서 만나야겠군
If not, I'll see you in court.
저 자는 누군가를
보호하려 하고 있어
He's protecting someone.
누군가에게 겁먹어 있거나
누군가를 보호해야 한다고 생각하는거야
Someone he's afraid of
or someone he cares about.
아버지 당신은 경사 시험을
보지 않으셨어요
He never took
his sergeant's test.
상관으로 승진하는 데에도
관심이 없으셨고요
Had no interest
in being a boss.
아버지는 생활비를 벌려고
투잡까지 뛰셨어요
He worked that second job
to make up for the money.
그렇게 돌아가실 줄은
생각도 하지 못했어요
I never thought
that's how he'd die.
제이슨 군...
Jason...
아버님 시신을 정말
꼭 보고 싶으세요?
is there any way
I can talk you out of this?
네
No.
아버지는
My father
저에게 있어서는 천하무적이었어요
was invincible in my eyes.
아버지가 어떻게 총을 맞아서
돌아가셨는지
I need to know
how it went down
확인해야만 하겠어요
and how he died.
첫번째 총알은 복부를 관통해
The first round entered
your father's abdomen,
창자에 구멍을 내고
perforating the bowel
척추 근처를 통과했다네
and coming to rest
near the spine.
그렇게 치명상을
입힐 정도는 아니었지
It was nonfatal.
두번째 총알은 여기를 통과해
The next round
entered here,
갈비뼈가 완전히
struck a rib,
으스러졌고,
shattering it.
우측 폐에 중상을 입히긴 했지만
There was significant damage
to the right lung,
마찬가지로 치명상이 되지는 않았어
but again,
it was nonfatal.
첫째, 둘째 총알은
0.9m~1.8m 정도 거리에서
These first two rounds
were fired from a distance
발사되었기 때문이야
of three to six feet.
이건 매우 가까이에서 발사되었는데
This one was close contact.
총을 안면에 대고
직접 발사한 것으로 보인다네
The gun was pressed
against his face.
그럼 아버지는..
So he was...
처형당하다시피
살해당하신 거네요
he was executed.
음...
Um...
길거리에 무기력하게
버려져서 말이죠?
Lying helpless on the ground?
어떤 놈의 인간이
그런 짓을 할 수 있죠?
What kind of human being
does that?
자네들 모두 약속이
있을 줄은 알고 있네
You all have
your assignments.
그래도 우리는 앤써니 롬바르도의
I want every family
member, every friend,
모든 가족, 친구, 과거 지인,
every past associate,
every codefendant
모든 공동피고인들을 조사해봐야 해
of Anthony Lombardo
spoken to.
그들이 집에 없으면
쫓아서 찾아내게.
If they aren't home,
track them down.
영장이 발부되어 있는 자들이면
여기로 끌고 오게
If they have a warrant,
drag them in.
말을 안 들으면
잘 회유해보게
If they don't, coax them in.
저 안에 사건 현장에서
롬바르도와 같이 있었던 사람이 있거나
Somebody on that list was
running with Lombardo last night
아니면 그 사실을 아는 사람이 있을거야
or knows who was.
그들이 범행에 사용한
도난차량에 대해
You all have the year,
make, model
연식, 메이커,
차종까지 확보된 상태야
of the stolen car
used in the robbery.
잘 주시해서 찾아봐
Keep your eyes open.
현장 근방에 버려뒀을
가능성이 높아
It's probably dumped
somewhere nearby.
자네들 중 어제밤부터
밤새 일한 사람이 많은 줄로 아네
I know some of you
have worked through the night.
혹시라도 힘들고 지칠 때가 오면
자네들보다 더 힘들어하고 있을
故 마크 라일리 경관의 유가족들을 생각하게
If you start feeling tired,
think of Mark Riley's family.
이제 일들 하게, 몸조심하고
Now get out there. Be safe.
롬바르도의 기록엔
절도죄가 전부예요
Lombardo's always
been a property thief...
경절도죄, 중절도죄,
마약절도 등등
burglary, grand larceny, drugs.
아무리 생각해도 경찰을
쏠만큼 대범한 인간이 아니예요
Seems so out of character
to shoot a cop.
그들은 라일리 경관에게
최루액 스프레이를 사용했어요
They came at Riley
with pepper spray.
현장에서 발견된 총은
라일리 경관의 것밖에 없었고요
And the only guns we know of
belonged to him.
아마 경찰을 쏘는 건
예상 외의 일이었을지도 몰라요
Maybe shooting a cop
wasn't part of the plan.
이런 류의 사건은 보통
내부 공모자가 벌인 짓일 가능성이 크지
Half these cases are
always inside jobs.
린지가 라일리 경관이 일했던
수표할인소에 가 있다네
Lindsay's working with
the owner of Bright-Star,
putting a list together of
current and former employees.
그쪽 관계자와 함께
현직, 전직 근무자들의
리스트를 뽑아오고 있어
브롱크스 관할 경찰서에서
방금 전화가 왔는데요
So, a sector from the Bronx
just called the desk downstairs.
차를 찾았대요
They found the car.
디건 고속도로 아래에 버려져 있었대요
Dumped under
the Deegan Expressway.
♪
일어나 자식아
Hey, get up.
왜 그래요?
What's going on?
라일리 경관이 죽었다네
Officer Riley passed away.
아! 이런..
Oh, God.
범행에 쓰인 차를 찾았다네
We have the car, Anthony.
네 공범 놈들의 지문이
군데군데 묻어 있더군
Your friends' prints
were all over it.
니 공범 놈들을 잡아오는건
It's just a matter of time
이제 시간 문제야
before your pals are sitting
in the room next door
너랑 똑같은 상황에 처하게 되겠지
in the same situation
that you are.
무슨 생각 들어?
What do you think?
걔들도 너네처럼 꿋꿋이
말 안하고 버틸 것 같아?
They gonna be stand-up like you?
당장 있는 건 너와 우리 뿐이니
You're here.
We're here.
거래를 하고 싶다면
기회는 지금 뿐이야
You want to make a deal,
now's the time to do it.
공범들이 잡혀오면
When they come
through that door,
니놈이 뭘 불든
이제 소용없어
all bets are off.
우리 경찰을 위해
한다고 생각하지 마
Don't do it for us.
Do it for her.
네 딸아이를 위해서 하는거야
자 이제 어떻게 할래 앤써니?
What's it gonna be, Anthony?
저는 할 말이 없어요
I got nothing to tell you.
넌 지금 대단히 큰 실수 하는거야
You're making
a very bad decision.
내 최선을 다해
네놈이 평생 후회하도록
And I'm gonna do my best
to make sure that you regret it
만들어 주지
for the rest of your life.
시장님과 지방검사에게 알리고 오겠네
I'm gonna brief
the mayor and the D.A.
한 시간 내로 돌아오도록 하지
I'll be back in an hour.
아직도 상황 파악이 안되는구만
You still don't get it.
아뇨, 형사님이 모르시는거예요
No, you don't get it.
밀고하면 전 죽어요
I snitch, I'm dead.
우리 딸애도 죽을 거예요
My girl is dead,
my daughter is dead.
무슨 말인지 알아요?
Do you understand that?
경찰이 너희 가족들을
지켜줄 수 있어
We can protect your family.
아뇨, 불가능해요
No, you can't.
반장님 말씀이 맞았네요
You were right.
누군가를 두려워하고 있어요
He is afraid of someone.
그래
Yeah.
그 두려움 때문에 경찰을
쏘기까지 하게 된 거지
So afraid, he's willing to take
the fall for killing a cop.
이것도 먹어
Here you go.
혹시 마음이 바뀌어서
진실을 진술한다면
I'll get you over to booking
when you're done eating.
밖에 데려나가서 더 근사한 걸
먹여줄 수도 있어
Unless you've had
a change of heart.
생각 바뀌지 않았어요
I didn't.
앞으로도 그럴 거고요
And I won't.
저거 누구예요?
무슨 일이예요?
Who's that?
What's going on?
저기 양복 입고 있는 사람이
지방검사님이야
The guy in the suit,
he's the D.A.
저 자를 아는가보군
You know who
the other guy is.
롤랜드 베니테즈지?
Roland Benitez.
저 자를 '무키'라고 불렀을테지
You probably call him Mookie.
범행 차량에서 저 자의 지문을 찾아서
체포했어. 저 자가 거래를 원하더군
We got his prints on the car;
he wants to make a deal.
그럴 리 없어요
No way.
그럴 리가 없어요
무키는 불지 않을거예요
No way.
Mookie's no snitch.
그러셔?
You don't think so?
그러면 저 자가 왜
지방검사랑 카메라랑 같이
'Cause they didn't bring
the D.A. and the camera in
취조실에 들어갔을까?
장기자랑 비디오라도 찍을려고?
to make a YouTube video.
무키가 저 방에 들어간건..
He might be in the room
with all that...
무키가 입을 열 리가 없어요
no, no way he's rolling on me.
네놈보다 무키의
작문실력이 훨씬 뛰어나구만
Mookie's definitely
a better speller.
누구예요?
What is that?
네놈보다 훨씬 먼저
They make you write
a confession
진실을 자백했구만
before you do a video.
네 친구놈이 널 물먹이려는것같은데?
Looks like he's putting
the gun in your hands.
보여줘봐요
Let me see that.
내가 왜 그래야 하지?
That would be unprofessional.
그거 가짜죠?
That ain't real, man.
내가 뭐 병신 호구로 보여요?
What, you think I'm stupid?
형씨들의 수작을
내가 모를줄 알아요?
I know
what you're doing.
날 속여먹으려는거죠?
Yeah, you're trying to fool me.
네놈은 이제 믿을수가 없는데
You give me too much credit,
Anthony.
날 법정으로 끌고 갈 수 있다면서요?
You said you're gonna
take me to court.
지금 당장 데려가지 그래요?
What are you waiting for?
내가 너한테 사기나
치고 있을 정도로
Do you really think
한가한 놈 같아보이냐?
that I'm playing
some kind of trick on you?
그래보이는데요?
Yeah, I do.
'백문이 불여일견'이라는 말은 알지?
You ever heard the expression
"seeing is believing"?
내가 무키가 지방검사에게
증언하는걸 보여주면 믿을 수 있어?
What if I let you see Mookie
talking to the D.A.?
그래야 믿을래?
Would you believe me then?
당신이 말하고 싶은것만
말해서도 안되고
You can't tell me the
truths you want to tell me.
내가 듣고 싶어하는것만
이야기해서도 안돼요
You can't just tell me
what I want to hear.
우리랑 거래를 하려면
In order for us
to make this deal,
모든걸 숨김없이 털어놔야 해요
you have to tell me
everything.
던, 저 자를 여기 들이면 안돼
Don, he can't be in here.
2초만요
Two seconds.
이 자식에게 직접
보여주고 싶어요
I want him to see
this for himself.
알겠어요, 거짓말은 않겠어요
Yeah, I'm not gonna lie.
그럼 범행 차량에 대해서 시작해보죠
Let's start with the car.
도난경보 시스템은 어떻게 했나요?
Were you worried about alarms?
도난경보 장치가 울릴때
By the time you hear the alarm
and you get to the window
저는 한블럭 아래에 있었죠
in your boxer shorts,
I'm halfway down the block...
- 저새끼 어디 있어요?
- 진정해.
- Where is he?
- Relax.
네 친구놈이 너에게
수갑을 채우려는가보군
He's about to put the final nail
넌 이제 끝났어
in your coffin, my friend.
You're done.
그러면 구체적으로 물어보죠
Okay, I'm gonna be very specific.
어제 차를 어떻게
훔쳤는지를 밝히고
I want to talk about the car
you stole yesterday.
범죄에 가담했던
공범들의 이름을 대세요
I want the names of the
people who were with you.
저 새끼 어디 있어요?
당장 얘기를 해야겠어요!
Where is he?
I want to talk to him right now!
- 진정해
- 저 자식이랑 얘기를 해야겠다고요!
- Calm down.
- No, I want to talk to him!
- 제가 경찰을 쏜게 아니예요
- 이봐!
- I didn't shoot that cop!
- Hey!
제가 경찰을 쏜게 아니라고요!
I didn't shoot that cop!
- 진정하라고!
- 저딴 모략에 당할 수는 없어요
- Calm down!
- I'm not going down for this.
지방검사와 이야기하게
해 주세요!
I want to talk
to the D.A.!
지금 당장요!
Right now, man!
거래를 하고 싶어요
I want to make
a deal, okay?
- 거래를 하고 싶다고요
- 알았어
- I want to make a deal.
- Okay.
네놈이 증언할 기회를 줄게
일단 가자
You'll have a chance
to tell your story. Let's go.
내가 저딴 모략에
I am not going down for this, man!
속아넘어갈 수 없어요!
내가 한 게 아니라고!
I didn't do this!
저새끼는 거짓말을 하고 있어요!
He's lying to you!
내가 한 게 아니라고!
I didn't do this!
모두들 잘 했네
드디어 저 자가 쓸모있게 되었어
Nice job everybody.
We got him.
Now we need to
find the third guy
이제 셋째놈을 잡아서
공범 중 누가 진짜
총을 쐈는지를 밝혀내야 해
and determine who actually
pulled the trigger.
재미있는거 전부 다 놓친건가요?
Looks like I missed all the fun.
그럼요
You did.
롬바르도를 도발하는 데에 성공했어요
I think we just
flipped Lombardo.
더 좋은 소식이 있어요
I've got more good news.
수표할인소에서 일했던
예전 근무자 중에
Guess whose name showed up
누구 이름이 있었게요?
on a list of former
Bright-Star employees.
- 롬바르도로군.
- 네
- Lombardo.
- Yep.
롬바르도는 3달간 거기에서
창구 안내원으로 일했어요
He worked there as a messenger
for three months
마크 라일리 경관과
같이 일했었고요
during the same time
that Mark Riley was there.
서로 알던 사이였어요
They knew each other.
앤써니가 무단 결근을 계속하자
They fired Anthony
six months ago
6개월전 해고되었고요
when he stopped
showing up for work.
앤써니가 내부 공모자였군
He's our inside man.
우리는 12살부터 불알친구였다고요!
We've been homeboys
since we were 12, man.
저 씹새끼가 저렇게
쉽게 배신을 때리다니!
I can't believe that bitch
turned on me like that.
앤써니, 이제 여기에서는
Anthony, when you're in here,
친구고 뭐고 없어
it's every man for himself.
그러니까 이제
So, right now,
네 자신을 생각해
it's about saving yourself.
"마크 라일리 경관,
시민들의 애도 속에서 영면하다"
너는 마크 라일리 경관과 구면이었어
You knew Mark Riley.
수표할인소에서 같이 일했던 사이지
You worked with him
at Bright-Star.
그 아저씨가 총에 맞는 일은
Look, him getting shot...
원래 절대 일어나지
말았어야 하는 일이었어요
that was never supposed to happen.
자넬 믿네 앤써니
I believe you.
하지만 더 이상 거짓말은 안 돼
But no more lies, Anthony.
지금 이 자리에서 모든 사실을
거짓 없이 이야기한다면
You tell me the
truth here and now,
자네를 전적으로 도와주겠네
I'll do everything
I can to help you.
하지만 거짓말이 한마디라도 있다면
But you lie to me just
once about anything,
네놈이 평생 감옥에서 썩게
I'll make sure you never live
to see the outside
만들어 주지
of a prison ever again.
알아듣겠나?
You understand?
저랑 롤랜드는..
Me and Roland...
몇주 전에 경찰이 들이닥쳐서
마약을 빼앗아간 덕분에
we owed Eric money for this
stash of weed we had to ditch
에릭에게 돈을 빚지게 되었어요
when the cops came at us
a few weeks ago.
빚은 상당했어요
It was a lot.
한 1만달러 상당이었죠
Like, ten grand worth.
에릭이라는 자의 성은 무엇인가?
What's Eric's last name?
무키라는 자는 모르던데
Mookie didn't know.
모를 리 없어요
He knows.
무키가 겁먹어서
말을 못하는것 뿐이예요
He didn't tell you
'cause he was scared.
에릭은..
Eric, man...
진짜 냉혈한 살인자예요
he's a stone-cold killer.
물불을 가리지 않죠
He's got bodies on him.
저한테 꼭 약속해주셔야 해요
You got to promise me
저희 가족들을 보호해주실 거라고요
that you're gonna
protect my family.
내가 약속하지
You have my word.
하..
Oh, man.
블레이락이예요
Blaylock.
에릭 블레이락이요
Eric Blaylock.
에릭, 에릭, 에릭,
Eric, Eric, Eric.
에릭 블레이락!
Eric Blaylock.
찾았어요
Got him.
그래서 수표할인소를 털어서
에릭에게 갚을 돈을 마련하려 했던 거군
So you decide to rob Bright-Star
as a way of paying Eric back.
에릭한테
I told him
저랑 롤랜드 둘이서
할 수 있다고 말했어요
that me and Roland
could do the job.
그러자 에릭은 저희 둘이
훔친 돈에서 땡전 하나 빼돌리지 않고
He says he's got to come with
자기에게 전부 갚을 것인지
to make sure I don't skim
any money from the top
자기 눈으로 확인해봐야겠다고
고집을 부렸어요
before he gets paid
what he's owed.
그런데 에릭은 미친놈이예요
But Eric's crazy.
저는 분명히 에릭한테
총을 사용하지 않고
I told him I wasn't gonna do it
돈을 훔칠거라고 말했어요
unless there was no guns.
배짱 넘치는군
That's pretty ballsy.
현직 경찰관을 총도 없이 털겠다니
Robbing a cop with no gun.
그 수표할인소가 어떻게 돌아가는지
다 알고 있으니까요
Nah, I knew the routine
from working there.
경찰 아저씨가 바지 우측에
총을 휴대하고 있다는걸 알고 있었죠
I knew Mark carried a gun
on his right side in his pants.
우리가 가면을 쓰고
최루액 스프레이를 뿌리면
I knew that if we came at him
with pepper spray, masks,
그 아저씨를 충분히 제압해서
총과 현금을 훔칠 수 있다고 생각했죠
we could beat him down,
get the gun and the cash.
정말로 성공했어요
We did it.
진짜 우리 작전이 먹혔다고요
It worked, man. We had it.
그런데 경찰아저씨가
I didn't know...
다른 총을 갖고 있을 줄은 몰랐어요
that he had another gun.
얼른 타!
Get in!
블레이락! 뉴욕 경찰이다!
멈춰!
Blaylock! NYPD, stop!
거기 서!
Stop right there!
손 들어!
Hands up!
두 팔 높이 들어!
Put your hands in the air!
살고 싶으면 당장
You want to live, put your hands
in the air, get on your knees!
두 팔 높이 들고
무릎 꿇어!
무릎 꿇으라고!
On your knees!
이 수갑 보이나?
See these cuffs?
네놈이 쏴죽인
경찰관의 것이지
They belong to the man you murdered.
그러셔?
Go ahead.
한 번 봐봐
Take a peek.
네놈이 이들을 알아볼 수 있다고 장담하지
I'm sure you recognize
these guys.
평생 듣도 보도 못한 놈들인데?
I've never seen them
before in my life.
이봐 거짓말은 작작 하자고
Come on.
이 자식 알지?
You know this guy?
몰라.
Nope.
그럼 이 자식은?
How 'bout him?
아는 놈이야?
You know him?
그럼 알다마다
Yeah, I know him.
정말 잘 알고 있지
I know him real good.
네놈들이 뭐라 하든
And no matter what you say,
어떻게 구슬리건 간에
what you do to him,
what you promise him,
그 인간(자신)은 어떤 것도 진술하지 않고
입도 굳게 닫아놓을 거야
he ain't writing nothing,
and he ain't saying nothing.
그러고보니
Matter of fact,
사진 속의 아저씨(자신)가
변호사를 불러달라고 하는것 같네?
I think he wants a lawyer.
저 찢어 죽일 놈의 새끼
Smug son of a bitch.
그나마 총상을 안입은걸
다행으로 생각해야지
He's lucky
he didn't catch a bullet.
좋아요, 일단 저 자를
All right,
at least we have him
린지나 로바토에 대한
for two counts
of attempted murder
살인미수로 잡아놨으니
빠져나갈 방법은 없을 거예요
on Lindsay and Lovato,
so he's not going anywhere.
골목에서 발견된 총은
라일리 경관의 것이 아닌 것으로 나타났어
The gun we recovered in the
alley wasn't Mark Riley's.
에릭의 집에 대해 수색 영장을
청구하고 있는 중이야
We're working on a search
warrant for Eric's place.
그래도 거기에서 나타날 거라고
기대하지는 말자고
Don't expect it
to turn up there.
차는 지문 하나 없이
깨끗한 상태예요
And the car was wiped clean.
저 자는 흔적을 지우는 데에
솜씨가 뛰어난 모양이예요
He did a good job of covering
his tracks up on that.
그래서 지금으로서는
저 자를 라일리 경관의 살인 혐의에 대해
So, as it stands right now,
we have no forensic evidence
연결시킬 어떠한 법의학적
증거도 없는 상태로군
that links him
to Mark Riley's murder.
증언이 필요해
We need a confession.
그건 힘들 것 같네요
That's not likely.
변호사를 불러달라고 하고 있어요
He just lawyered up.
그래도..
Well...
그건 우리가 저 자에게
물어봐야 소용 없다는것 뿐이지
that just means
we can't talk to him.
아마 다른 누군가는
저 자의 입을 열게 할 수 있을거야
But maybe somebody else can.
♪
내가 자백한 게 아니야!
I didn't give you up.
정말이야 맹세해
I swear to God, man.
맹세컨대 무키가 우리를
팔아넘긴거야!
I swear to God,
Mookie flipped on us.
무키가 모든 것을
경찰에 털어놨어!
Man, he gave up the whole thing.
이 멍청한 새끼야!
You stupid bastard.
내 말 들어
Listen to me.
말 좀 들어봐
그 자식이 자백을 했어
Dude wrote a confession.
내가 직접 봤어
그 자식이 우리를 전부 팔아넘겼어
I saw it;
he flipped on both of us.
닥쳐!
Shut up!
에릭..
Eric...
무키는 어떤 것도 자백하지 않았어
Mookie didn't
give anything up.
걘 죽었거든
Mookie's dead.
아냐, 그럴 리 없어
무키가 자백하는걸 내 눈으로 봤는데
No, man, he isn't.
He can't be. I saw him.
나도 내 눈으로 봤어!
And I saw him, too.
그 경찰놈이
도망가던 무키의 다리를
I saw that cop
shoot him in the leg
정확히 명중한걸 봤지
while he was
running away.
앞자리에 앉아 가던 내내
He bled out in the front seat
무키는 피를 철철 흘렸어
of the car right
in front of me.
무키가 죽는걸 내 눈으로 봤다고!
I watched him die.
그래서 무키의 시체를
트렁크에다가 버렸지
Then I shoved him in the trunk
of the car.
아냐, 그럴 리 없어
No, that's not possible.
진짜로 내가 내 눈으로 봤다니까!
I'm telling you, man,
I saw it with my own eyes.
무키가 지방검사에게
증언을 하던걸 영상으로 봤다고!
He was making the video, man.
He was talking to the D.A.!
그런 영상은 없어!
There is no video!
He didn't confess!
무키는 증언 같은걸 하지 않았어!
경찰들이 널 갖고 논거야
앤써니
They played you, Anthony.
경찰들이 널 속인거라고
Those cops played you.
베니테즈 씨, 도난경보 장치는
어떻게 했나요?
Were you worried
about alarms, Mr. Benitez?
도난경보 장치요?
Alarms?
도난경보 장치가 울릴 때
By the time
저는 한 블럭 아래에서
you hear the alarm,
I'm halfway down the block
위성 라디오를 듣고 있었죠
listening to your satellite radio.
♪
도난경보 장치요?
Alarms?
도난경보 장치가 울릴 때
저는 한 블럭 아래에서
By the time you hear the alarm,
I'm halfway down the block
위성 라디오를 듣고 있었죠
listening to your satellite radio.
경찰들한테 내가
그 짭새를 쐈다고 증언했어?
Did you tell them
I shot the cop?
증언한거야?
Did you?
이미 다 알고 있다구
They already knew, man.
맹세컨대 무키가 이미 불었다고!
I swear it, Mookie told them.
무키는 뒈졌다고!
There is no Mookie!
이 병신 내가 죽여버릴꺼야!
I'm gonna kill you.
제발 날 믿어
Come on, man.
이 수갑이 풀리자마자
네놈을 죽여버릴꺼야
The first chance I get,
I'm gonna kill you!
넌 속은거야
이 멍청한 새끼야
You got played,
you stupid bitch!
넌 속았다고!
You got played.
끝났군, 완벽해
Done.
Done!
우리보고 거저 먹으라고
In the boat.
아주 완벽히 잘 차려줬구만
Filleted, pan-fried, on the plate.
정말 완벽했어요
Oh, that was perfect.
앤써니의 증언에 더불어
Anthony's statement
plus Blaylock's
블레이락이 증언을
뒷받침해줬어요
corroborating statement gives us
흉악 살인사건에 대해
저 둘이서 완벽한 증거를 만들어줬어요
a rock-solid felony murder
case against both guys.
Yeah, thank God
for civilized lies.
Yeah, thank God for civilized lies.
이런 통쾌한 순간 때문에
It's moments like
these remind me
내가 이 일을 사랑하는 거지
how much I love this job.
딱 한번만 칭찬하도록 하죠.
I'm only gonna say this once.
취조실에서 펼친 활약
정말 멋졌어요.
Did an amazing job in that room.
고마워.
Thank you.
그래, 우리 일은
이제 끝난 것 같군.
Yeah, our work is done here.
정리하고 퇴근하자고
Let's wrap it
up and go home.
메서 형사님
Detective Messer,
- 찾아와주셔서 감사합니다.
- 아녜요
- thank you for coming.
- Oh, not at all.
이쪽은 제 남편 대니예요
This is my
husband, Danny.
안녕하세요,
Hey. How you doing?
고인의 명복을 빕니다.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
맨하탄에서 근 20년동안 일한
You should know, every cop
모든 경찰들은
that worked in Manhattan
for the past 20 years...
고인을 기억하고 있어요
they knew your father.
고인은 정말 특별하신 경찰이었어요
He was something special.
고맙습니다
Thank you, guys.
잠시 들어오시겠어요?
Uh, can you, you know,
come in for a second?
- 뭐라도 좀 드세요
- 고맙지만 괜찮아요.
- Have bite to eat?
- Oh, no. Thank you.
조의를 표하러 온 것 뿐이예요
We just wanted
to pay our respects.
그리고 참 드리고 싶은 게 있어요
And, uh, I wanted
to give you something.
증거보관실에
잘 얘기해서 가져왔어요
I made a few phone calls.
가지셔도 돼요
It's yours.
물론 경찰학교에서
졸업하기 전까지
Course, you don't get to
wear it till you graduate
이걸 차고 다니면 안되지만..
from the academy, but...
제복에 끼워볼때마다
every time you pin it
on your uniform,
고인을 추억하고
고인의 의지를 회상할 수 있을 거예요
you can think of your dad
and what he represented.
아드님은 저에게뿐만 아니라
I'd say make him proud,
고인께도 이미 충분히
자랑스러운 아들로 기억될 거예요
but... he already was.
진심으로 감사드려요
Thank you for everything.
실례하겠습니다
Excuse me.
아빠의 경찰 뱃지예요
They, uh, gave me Dad's badge.
한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
재배포 허용. 수정은 제작자와 협의 하에